

PROFILE

An emerging systems engineer, with an introductory knowledge of Google Cloud, an extensive background of leadership and experience in various organizations and trades including in the agriculture and political fields. Intent on mastering the uses of machine learning while earning multitude of certifications including but not limited to the Cisco CCNA and CCSP, and Google Cloud Architect, and AWS certifications.

CONTACT

PHONE: 773.430.4461

WEBSITE:

www.linkedin.com/in/johnhayes48

EMAIL:

jahayesjr.37@gmail.com

PROFICIENCIES

- Microsoft Office Suite
- Data analysis
- Public Speaking
- Canvassing Training Facilitator
- 12-Line Phone Systems
- Leadership
- Fundraising
- Policy Consulting
- Analytics

JOHN ANTHONY HAYES, JR.

EDUCATION

Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, Tennessee (In progress)

B.S in Political Science (Pre-Law)- Public administration, Computer Science

WORK EXPERIENCE

Google- Cloud Engineering Fellow

June 2021 - Present

Was a part of a new pilot program, sponsored by Google in which students were taught the basics of coding, as well as introduced to the infrastructure of Google Cloud. Obtaining the Google Cloud Digital Leader and Associate Cloud Engineer certifications are the main objectives of this course.

Everest Campus (Student Quarters) - Leasing Consultant

August 2018 - January 2020

Led a group of leasing consultants and trained several more as we increased lease sales by 30% in one of our locations, while serving as support tech for all three of them. supervised a group of technicians as we updated our network infrastructure in our 93-unit apartment complex. Served as first level support for server maintenance.

Karl Dean for Governor - Intern

June 2017 - July 2018

Demonstrated my teaching ability by leading and training a network of 120 canvassers and volunteers that stretched the northwest portion of Middle Tennessee. Furthermore analyzed statistics, policies, and implemented machine learning to maximize donations from prospective donors. Also performed data entry and general IT setup to set up a gubernatorial run for Karl Dean.

LEADERSHIP

Weakley County Democratic Party

- Executive Board (2017-2019)
- Candidate Recruitment Chairman (2018)

College Democrats of America

- National Black Caucus Vice President/ Secretary 2017-2019
- National Black Caucus President (Acting) (2019-present)